

Lester Luigui Narvasta Ramirez Mobile Engineer

(+51) 972579013

lesternr@gmail.com

Lima - Perú

https://www.linkedin.com/in/lester-narvasta-ramirez/

Mobile Software Developer with 5+ years of experience in a broad range of industries, solid understanding on software development life cycles, UX, analytics and agile methodologies.

Dedicated to continuously learning, developing and adopting new technologies, oriented to create business and experimental Apps.

I enjoy working as a team member that understands how important it is to build innovative features and achieve goals working together with stakeholders.

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

Development

Android

- Android Studio Android Architecture Components(Coroutines, LiveData, Databinding)
- o Clean Architecture MVVM, MVI, MVP, Dependency injection with Hilt.
- Audio and Video stream, websockets for real time communication.
- o Data transmission to other devices through Bluetooth 2.0 & 4.0, Beacon, Arduino board, USB.
- API Rest

iOS

- XCode and Distribution to testflight and AppStore
- TouchID/FaceID
- Notifications, Universal link, Apple Watch

Platforms

- Google Maps SDK (GMaps, Routes, Places, etc), Firebase Platform (Notification, Crashlytics, Analytics, Firestore, Remote Config, Authentication, Performance)
- o Git, Github, Bitbucket, Jira, Confluence, Trello, Slack, Postman, Braze, Lottie, Apollo GraphQL.
- o Continuous Integration Github Actions, Jenkins, Pipeline, Bitrise.

Others

- o Arduino Data transmission via Bluetooth, USB.
- C++ for Algorithm Competitions
- Web Frontend HTML5, JavaScript, AngularJS, Bootstrap.
- Web Backend Php, Java, NodeJS
- Database MySQL, SQLServer, PostgreSQL.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Android Engineer @ SweatWorks - https://www.sweatworks.com

October 2019 - Present (2 years 6 months)

Openfit(MyxFitness App): https://www.openfit.com

- Work closely with other developers and designers to develop new features, code refactor and improvements.
- Create custom libraries and develop internal tools to share with other projects.
- Work closely with external teams that provide third party libraries (North Pole Engineering, FeedFm).
- Manage different service tools used for development help. (Analytics, performance, crashlytics, campaigns).
- App distribution through mdm System, for beta users and release.

BODi: https://www.beachbodyondemand.com/bodi

- Implement new features and include some refactors for hardware related features.
- Work closely with the hardware team and add features for bluetooth sensors.
- Automate builds for local debug, QA and release candidates.

• Mobile Software Engineer @ Verizon Enterprise - http://www.verizonenterprise.com October 2016 - October 2019 (3 years)

My verizon for enterprise App(Android/iOS):

- Collaborate with stakeholders to define plans and be aligned with the road map, deliver requirements and provide technical support.
- Refactoring project to implement MVP pattern and work with a team in a collaborative way in order to improve the quality of code.
- Automation of testing, building and delivery process through Jenkins Tool.
- Reduce crash reports and customer complaints by using Fabric Crashlytics, Firebase Crashlytics, and Firebase Performance.
- Work closely with Android Analytics and Firebase Analytics and metrics to understand customer behavior on new features.

Verizon customer relationship management(Android/iOS)

- Create the app from scratch and organize the project architecture, define the base and git flow for development and app distribution.
- Collect the requirements and define the scopes according to sprint goals.

Mobile Software Engineer @ SGTel - sgtel.pe

January 2015 - September 2016 (1 Year 8 months)

Systems analyst and mobile developer In charge of Android Application applying Material Design, GeoLocation, Social Network Connected and multiples tools, mvp, clean architecture.

Software Engineer @ Huahlabs - http://huahlabs.com/

July 2014 - December 2014. (5 months)

Research and Development of several web (AngularJS) and small mobile (Android) applications.

• Intern @ Softmark Peru S.A.C - http://www.smperu.com

April 2012 - November 2012 (8 months)

In Charge of developing web applications as frontend and backend for web projects.

• Other Contributions in Apps Development

- Delcomp: Developed customs and experimental apps to communicate with hardware devices.
- DevsolutionTI: Define and organize the structure for the project including tools and development framework.

LANGUAGE SKILLS

- English Upper-Intermediate
- Portuguese Elementary Proficiency
- Spanish Native Speaker

TRAINING

- Aug-12-2013 Universidad Católica Santo Toribio de Mogrovejo Chiclayo
 XX Congreso Nacional de Estudiantes de Ingeniería Sistemas y Computación.
- Feb-11-2013 2013-February-09 Universidad Católica San Pablo Arequipa Campamento Peruano de Programación 2013
- Aug-24-2013 Universidad Nacional de Ingeniería Lima Campamento Peruano de Programación UNI 2013
- Mar-11-2014 Universidad Nacional de Ingeniería Lima Campamento Peruano de Programación UNI 2014

AWARDS

- August-12-2012 Third Place
 Programming Contest XX Coneisc Universidad Santo Toribio de Mogrovejo(Chiclayo)
- February-07-2013 First Place
 Programming Contest SECICOMP 2013 Universidad Nacional de Trujillo (Trujillo)
- September-13-2013 Fourth Place
 IV Peruvian Programming Contest SPC Universidad Señor de Sipan (Chiclayo)
- November-21-2013 First Place
 Il Feria Tecnológica de Ingeniería Informática Universidad Nacional Jose Faustino Sanchez Carrion(Huacho)

UNDERGRADUATE COMPETITIONS

- November-10-2012
 ACM-ICPC Regional Programming Contest/South America
- November-09-2013
 ACM-ICPC Regional Programming Contest/South America
- October-26-2013
 IEE Extreme Programming Competition 7.0

CERTIFICATIONS

- Scrum Master Certified (SMC)
 https://certification.scrumalliance.org/accounts/875652-lester-luigui/certifications/994010-csm
- Dev.Ops Engineering on AWS https://drive.google.com/open?id=0B3jr10jVBZONRElaTHBhSnJWbWlwSmVIRIR5UkJ3WnpkMnJ j